A Guide to the Ford Foundation records, News Releases FA745
Rockefeller Archive Center
- News Releases, volume 19, 1973 January 9 - 1974 January 7; 1 Bound Volumes (Box 9)
  - Graduate fellowships, 1973-1974 academic year, for American Indians, Mexican Americans, Puerto Ricans, and Black Americans, 1973 October 1 (Box 9)
  - Ford Foundation and Public Broadcasting, 1973 August 23 (Box 9)
  - Government of Indonesia, oral history program, 1973 August 31 (Box 9)
  - ‘Ford Foundation Letter’ Special Report: Economic Muscle for La Raza, 1973 September 15 (Box 9)
  - Grants for innovative undergraduate programs at 12 colleges and universities in the Midwest, 1973 July 24 (Box 9)
  - Ability of minorities to enter the country’s economic mainstream, 1973 July (Box 9)
  - Forthcoming reports supported by Ford Foundation grants: (1) “Setting National Priorities: The 1974 Budget”, (2) Employment and Addiction, (3) Electoral Reform, (4) The World Bank Since Bretton Woods, (5) “Model Cities Impact on Better Communities”, (6) The World Economic Order, 1973 July 10 (Box 9)
  - Grant to Arena Stage, Washington D.C., 1973 July 9 (Box 9)
  - “An Inquiry into the Uses of Instructional Technology”, 1973 June 25 (Box 9)
  - Grants to La Raza Investment Corporation, Spanish Speaking Unity Council, and Mexican American Unity Council, 1973 June 12 (Box 9)
  - ‘Ford Foundation Letter’ Special Report: Building a New Generation of Arms Control Analysts, 1973 June 15 (Box 9)
  - Queen’s University Belfast social science research, 1973 May 30 (Box 9)
  - “They Can Go Home Again: Young Rural Educators and Leaders Reverse Talent Drain from Remote Areas” by Charles Childs, 1973 May (Box 9)
  - Community development corporations (CDCs) program report, 5 years, $75 million, 1973 May 14 (Box 9)
  - Reverse the decay of urban housing through the combined efforts of local residents, private capital, local government, and private foundations, 1973 April 16 (Box 9)
  - Sanford M. Jaffe appointment, Officer in Charge of the Government and Law office, 1973 April 16 (Box 9)
  - Forthcoming reports: (1) Aid to Veterans: “Swords into Plowshares: Our GI Bill”, (2) The FCC and Television: “Economic Aspects of Television Regulation”, (3) Teacher Corps Evaluated: Reform and Organizational Survival: The Teacher Corps as an Instrument of Educational Change”, (4) Neighborhood Government, (5) Black Suburbanization, (6) Model Cities Examined, 1973 April 13 (Box 9)
  - Appointments: Marshall A. Robinson, Deputy Vice President, Office of Resources and Environment; Earl F. Cheit, Officer in Charge, Office of Higher Education and Research; Sanford M. Jaffe, Officer in Charge, Office of Government and Law, 1973 April 16 (Box 9)
  - Publishing ventures through which students of different cultural backgrounds may recapture their heritage; ‘Chicano Chronicle’ and ‘Black Chronicle’ newspapers; ‘Foxfire’, 1973 April (Box 9)
  - Soedjatmoko elected to Board of Trustees, 1973 April 2 (Box 9)
  - “The Public Interest Law Firm: New Voices for New Constituencies” report published, 1973 March 23 (Box 9)
  - Development assistance review of 1972, and interim review planned for 1977; 1972 Annual Report summary, 1973 March 19 (Box 9)
  - Municipal conservation commissions in the Northeast (Lists of recipients arranged by state), 1973 March 5 (Box 9)
  - Grants to 13 universities for research on problems common to advanced industrial societies, 1973 February 21 (Box 9)
  - Efforts aimed at eliminating housing segregation and promoting low-income housing development, particularly in the suburbs, 1973 January 31 (Box 9)
  - ‘Ford Foundation Letter’ Special Report: Symphonic Strains (Financial), 1973 February 1 (Box 9)
  - Merrimon Cuninggim appointment, Advisor on Program Management, Office of the President, 1973 January 15 (Box 9)
  - ‘Corporate Social Responsibility and the Institutional Investor’ report published, 1973 January 9 (Box 9)
- News Releases, volume 20, 1975 January 27 - 1975 December 16; 1 Bound Volumes (Box 10)
- News Releases, 1975 (Box 10)
  - World economic relations, 1975 January 27 (Box 10)
  - Richard C. Sheldon announcement, Director, Office of the Arts, 1975 January 27 (Box 10)
  - Recording–Publications Program, 1975 March 3 (Box 10)
  - International Women’s Year Tribune, 1975 March 24 (Box 10)
  - 1974 Annual Report, 1975 March 31 (Box 10)
  - Greek arts, 1975 June 4 (Box 10)
  - Harvey P. Hall obituary, 1975 June 19 (Box 10)
  - Fellowships for refugee intellectuals, 1975 July 25 (Box 10)
  - Housing grants, 1975 September 9 (Box 10)
  - Environmental disputes, 1975 September 22 (Box 10)
  - International economics, 1975 September 25 (Box 10)
  - Hedley Donovan announcement, election to Board of Trustees, 1975 October 16 (Box 10)
  - Indochina fellowships, 1975 November 13 (Box 10)
  - European studies, 1975 November 24 (Box 10)
  - Vietnam veterans study, 1975 December 16 (Box 10)
- News Releases, 1976 (Box 10)
  - Nuclear Energy, 1976 January 20 (Box 10)
  - Ralf Dahrendorf, election to Board of Trustees, 1976 February 9 (Box 10)
  - Robert H. Maybury evaluation "Technical Assistance and Innovation in Science Education" published in the journal Science Education, 1976 February 17 (Box 10)
  - Stanley W. Gregory obituary, 1976 February 18 (Box 10)
  - 1975 Annual Report, 1976 May 14 (Box 10)
  - Kalman Silvert obituary, 1976 June 15 (Box 10)
  - Greek art, 1976 June 22 (Box 10)
  - Production of New American plays, 1976 July 15 (Box 10)
  - Glen E. Watts, 1976 July 22 (Box 10)
  - Public Television, 1976 August 5 (Box 10)
  - John A. Quinn obituary, 1976 August 23 (Box 10)
  - Midcareer journalism fellowships in international security and arms control, 1976 September 7 (Box 10)
  - Ford Foundation Letter’, 1976 October 1 (Box 10)
  - Open Housing, 1976 September 27 (Box 10)
  - Jon L. Halger announcement, 1976 October 12 (Box 10)
  - Howard Dressner announcement, 1976 October 27 (Box 10)
  - Mitchell Sviridoff release re: poverty, crime, unemployment, and welfare dependency, 1976 November 18 (Box 10)
  - Roy Greep Report (“Reproduction and Human Welfare: A Challenge to Research”), 1976 December 16 (Box 10)
- News Releases, 1977 (Box 10)
  - Henry Ford II, resignation from Board of Trustees, 1977 January 12 (Box 10)
  - Nuclear Power, 1977 March 21 (Box 10)
  - Ford Foundation Letter’, 1977 April 1 (Box 10)
  - State Environmental Competition, 1977 April 14 (Box 10)
  - 1976 Annual Report, 1977 May 11 (Box 10)
  - Franklin A. Thomas – Trustee, 1977 June 29 (Box 10)
  - New American Plays Program, 1977 September 19 (Box 10)
  - New Trustees: Nina Garsoian, Donald Perkins, Harriet Rabb, Edson W. Spencer, 1977 October 9 (Box 10)
- News Releases, 1978 (Box 10)
  - Coal Policy, 1978 March 22 (Box 10)
  - 1977 Annual Report, 1978 April 9 (Box 10)
  - Ford Foundation 'Letter’, 1978 April 1 (Box 10)
  - Rodrigo Botero Montoya, election to Board of Trustees, 1978 April 13 (Box 10)
  - Environment, 1978 April 24 (Box 10)
  - Indian Rights, Indian Law, 1978 May 4 (Box 10)
  - Mortgage Funds, 1978 May 5 (Box 10)
  - Child Care, 1978 May 22 (Box 10)
  - Violent Delinquents: A Report to the Ford Foundation from the Vera Institute of Justice, 1978 July 9 (Box 10)
  - Irving S. Shapiro, election to Board of Trustees, 1978 July 2 (Box 10)
  - Ervin Nyiregyhazi, International Piano Archvies, CBS Records, 1978 July 13 (Box 10)
  - New American Plays Program, 1978 December 5 (Box 10)
  - Grants for research on the U.S. Presidency, 1978 July 17 (Box 10)
  - Grants for development of new contraceptives, 1978 November 6 (Box 10)
- News Releases, 1979 (Box 10)
  - Urban-Oriented Colleges, 1979 January 2 (Box 10)
  - Franklin A. Thomas - President, 1979 January 30 (Box 10)
  - Community of Peace People of Northern Ireland, 1979 February 5 (Box 10)
  - Minority Commission, and American Higher Education, 1979 February 13 (Box 10)
  - 1978 Annual Report, 1979 May 16 (Box 10)
  - Women’s programs, “Financial Support of Women’s Programs I the 1970s: A Review of Private and Government Funding in the United States and Abroad”, 1979 July 18 (Box 10)
  - Minority postdoctoral Fellowship program, 1979 September 4 (Box 10)
  - Adult illiteracy in the U.S., 1979 September 9 (Box 10)
  - American workers in Europe, 1979 October 30 (Box 10)
- News Releases, 1980 (Box 10)
  - Alvin N. Puryear – VP, 1980 February 4 (Box 10)
  - New York City efforts to upgrade basic academic skills, 1980 February 19 (Box 10)
  - Katherine Busboom Magrath – Director of Equity Investments, 1980 March 19 (Box 10)
  - MACE (Mississippi Action for Community Education)/Delta Foundation, 1980 March 25 (Box 10)
  - 1979 Annual Report, 1980 May 25 (Box 10)
  - LISC (Local Initiatives Support Corporation), 1980 May 23 (Box 10)
  - Yale Law journalists, 1980 July 22 (Box 10)
  - ‘Women in the World’, 1980 December 22 (Box 10)
- News Releases, 1981 (Box 10)
  - New Organizational Framework, 1981 April 6 (Box 10)
  - 1980 Annual Report, 1981 June 28 (Box 10)
  - Population, 1981 June 29 (Box 10)
  - Energy Costs, 1981 July 23 (Box 10)
  - Zimmerman appointment, 1981 July 27 (Box 10)
  - Minorities and Math, 1981 August 27 (Box 10)
  - College and University desegregation, 1981 September 8 (Box 10)
  - Educational programs, 1981 September 22 (Box 10)
  - John English appointment, 1981 October 9 (Box 10)
  - ‘Left-Handed Fastballers’ report, 1981 October 22 (Box 10)
  - Nonfiction Writers Awards, 1981 November 17 (Box 10)
  - Donald McHenry election, 1981 November 27 (Box 10)
  - LAWASIA, Human Rights in Asia, 1981 December 8 (Box 10)
  - Linda Strumpf appointment, 1981 December 16 (Box 10)
  - Gladys Chang Hardy appointment, 1981 December 21 (Box 10)
- News Releases, 1982 (Box 10)
  - Carol A. Zipkin appointment, 1982 January 8 (Box 10)
  - Allen Faurot appointment, 1982 January 15 (Box 10)
  - Higher Education-Minorities, 1982 January 28 (Box 10)
  - City High School Recognition, 1982 February 2 (Box 10)
  - Mary Lynn Walker appointment, 1982 February 23 (Box 10)
  - Teenage Pregnancy Fund Increase, 1982 April 19 (Box 10)
  - Announcement of Winners in city High School Program, 1982 May 18 (Box 10)
  - Paul F. Miller Jr. Elected to Trustees, 1982 July 2 (Box 10)
  - John J. Koproski appointment, 1982 July 23 (Box 10)
  - MDRC (Manpower Demonstration Research Corporation), 1982 September 17 (Box 10)
  - SSRC (Social Science Research Council) and ACLS (American Council of Learned Societies), 1982 September 26 (Box 10)
  - City High Schools, Phase II, 1982 October 5 (Box 10)
  - Fair Start for Children, 1982 October 26 (Box 10)
  - Barbara Scott Preiskel, 1982 December 9 (Box 10)
- News Releases, 1983 (Box 10)
  - William Milliken appointment, 1983 February 14 (Box 10)
  - Thomas Wyman appointment, 1983 March 1 (Box 10)
  - City high Schools, 1983 April 12 (Box 10)
  - City high Schools, 1983 June 14 (Box 10)
  - Teenage Pregnancy, 1983 June 29 (Box 10)
  - 1982 Annual Report, 1983 June 30 (Box 10)
  - Northern Trust Company, 1983 June 28 (Box 10)
  - A. Bartlette Giamatti – Trustee, 1983 July 6 (Box 10)
  - National Arts Stabilization Fund, 1983 July 26 (Box 10)
  - Community Colleges, 1983 September 12 (Box 10)
  - Refugees and Migrants, 1983 October 2 (Box 10)
  - Opening of Dakar Field Office, 1983 December 5 (Box 10)
  - Barron M. Tenny promotion, 1983 December 27 (Box 10)
- News Releases, 1984 (Box 10)
  - Arson control, 1984 February 16 (Box 10)
  - Arms control comp., 1984 March 5 (Box 10)
  - 1983 Annual Report, 1984 April 10 (Box 10)
  - Franklin A. Thomas - Cooper Union Speech, 1984 May 23 (Box 10)
  - P/PV (Public/Private Ventures) – STEP (Summer Training and Education Program), 1984 June 22 (Box 10)
  - Haitian Task Force, 1984 October 3 (Box 10)
  - Community colleges, 1984 October 22 (Box 10)
  - Whitney M. Young lecture, 1984 October 24 (Box 10)
  - Foundation partnership announces major grants to neighborhood groups, 1984 January 16 (Box 10)
- News Releases, 1985 (Box 10)
  - Welfare program, 1985 January 24 (Box 10)
  - Math collaborative, 1985 March 18 (Box 10)
  - 1984 Annual Report, 1985 April 16 (Box 10)
  - Doctoral Fellowship program, 1985 May 1 (Box 10)
  - State and local government, 1985 September 2 (Box 10)
  - Teen fathers, 1985 October 1 (Box 10)
  - Improving undergraduate education, 1985 December 26 (Box 10)
- News Releases, 1986 (Box 10)
  - Social Science Research Council (SSRC)/Foreign Policy Fellowships, 1986 February 11 (Box 10)
  - 1985 Annual Report, 1986 May 18 (Box 10)
  - “National Service: What Would it Mean?” by Danzig and Szanton, 1986 June 5 (Box 10)
  - 25 Finalists /Innovations in State and Local Government, 1986 July 23 (Box 10)
  - U.S./Mexico Commission, 1986 September 11 (Box 10)
  - Innovations in State and Local Government, 10 Winners, 1986 September 25 (Box 10)
  - Henry Schacht – Trustee, 1986 October 20 (Box 10)
  - Preventing High School Dropouts, 1986 November 18 (Box 10)
  - U.S. Rural Economy, 1986 December 30 (Box 10)
- News Releases, 1987 (Box 11)
  - Community Foundations, 1987 January 20 (Box 11)
  - 1986 Annual Report, 1987 March 31 (Box 11)
  - National Resource Center for Children in Poverty (Joint Ford Foundation-Carnegie Corporation), 1987 June 22 (Box 11)
  - Innovations in State and Local Government (22 finalists, 18 individual press releases of finalists), 1987 June 30 (Box 11)
  - Opening of China Field Office, 1987 July 2 (Box 11)
  - Fund for Research on Dispute Resolution, 1987 September 29 (Box 11)
  - Trustee- General Olusegun Obasanjo, 1987 September 18 (Box 11)
  - Innovations in State and Local Government Awards – 10 winners, 1987 September 17 (Box 11)
  - Press Advisory –Trustees in Miami, 1987 October 7 (Box 11)
  - 3 new Trustees: Burke, Hogg, Jordan, 1987 November (Box 11)
  - New Chairman, Edson W. Spencer, 1987 December 17 (Box 11)
- News Releases, 1988 (Box 11)
  - Changing Relations, 1988 January 28 (Box 11)
  - Dropout Prevention, 1988 February 11 (Box 11)
  - 1987 Annual Report, 1988 April 22 (Box 11)
  - Emergency Housing (EHAP), 1988 May 5 (Box 11)
  - AIDS /Council on Foundations, 1988 April 25 (Box 11)
  - Innovations in State and Local Government (Finalists), 1988 June 30 (Box 11)
  - Innovations in State and local Government (10 winners), 1988 September 30 (Box 11)
  - MDRC (Manpower Demonstration Research Corporation) - Project Redirection, 1988 October 7 (Box 11)
  - Social Sciences Initiative for Undergraduate Education, 1988 October 28 (Box 11)
  - Reforming Teacher Education, 1988 November 29 (Box 11)
- News Releases, 1989 (Box 11)
  - Ford and MacArthur Foundations announce new grants to Community Foundations, 1989 January 20 (Box 11)
  - Social Welfare and the American Future: the Common Good, 1989 May 11 (Box 11)
  - National Center for Children, 1989 May 22 (Box 11)
  - Opening of new field office in Harare, Zimbabwe, 1989 May 23 (Box 11)
  - New Trustee – M.S. Swaminathan, 1989 June 27 (Box 11)
  - Black and Hispanic Art Museums, 1989 July 31 (Box 11)
  - QUASAR (Quantitative Understanding: Amplifying Student Achievement and Reasoning), 1989 October 16 (Box 11)
  - New Trustees – Fergusson and Ridings, 1989 November 30 (Box 11)
  - Ford Foundation to make grants in Soviet Union, Eastern Europe, 1989 December 13 (Box 11)
- News Releases, 1990 (Box 11)
  - Higher Ed. Leaders Join FF in announcing $1.6 million to improve Race relations and Campus Diversity, 1990 February 13 (Box 11)
  - New Trustee – David T. Kearns, 1990 April 12 (Box 11)
  - Ford Foundation Supports New Performing Art with $750,000 in grants, 1990 May 7 (Box 11)
  - Ford Foundation grants $1.9 million to invigorate Black and Hispanic Art Museums (2nd round), 1990 September 21 (Box 11)
  - Innovations in State and Local Government, 1990 June 22 (Box 11)
  - Good News about Government: ‘Innovating America’, 1990 July 25 (Box 11)
  - Ford Foundation program addresses cultural diversity on college campuses, 1990 September 12 (Box 11)
  - 10 successful government programs cited for innovation by the Ford Foundation and Harvard, 1990 September 28 (Box 11)
  - Ford Foundation and Dag Hammarskjold Foundation release report calling for bold changes at U.N., 1990 September 18 (Box 11)
  - Ford Foundation grants $3.8 million to bolster fellowships and internships in public and international law, 1990 November 2 (Box 11)
  - Ford Foundation grants $2.5 million to foster transfers from 2 to 4 year colleges (ACE), 1990 December 14 (Box 11)
  - Ford Foundation grants $3.6 million for studies of new approaches to arms control and peacekeeping, 1990 December 18 (Box 11)
- News Releases, 1991 (Box 11)
  - Leadership program for community foundations, Ford and MacArthur Foundations, 1991 January 23 (Box 11)
  - Innovations in State and Local Government (25 finalists), 1991 June 21 (Box 11)
  - New Trustee – Luis Nogales, 1991 July 25 (Box 11)
  - New Director, Office of Communications – Lloyd Garrison, 1991 August 5 (Box 11)
  - Black and Hispanic Art Museums (3rd round), 1991 September 17 (Box 11)
  - Innovations in State and Local Government (winners), 1991 September 25 (Box 11)
  - New Trustee: Robert D. Haas, 1991 December 30 (Box 11)
- News Releases, 1992 (Box 11)
  - Alison Bernstein named director of Education and Culture, 1992 April 2 (Box 11)
  - 73 public programs names Innovations award semifinalists by Ford Foundation and Harvard University, 1992 April 6 (Box 11)
  - Innovations in State and Local Government, 25 finalists, 1992 July 13 (Box 11)
  - New advisory group to recommend steps to end U.N.’s financial crisis, 1992 September 15 (Box 11)
  - Innovations in State and Local Governments, 10 winners, 1992 September 24 (Box 11)
  - Joan Dassin named director of Latin America and Caribbean Programs, 1992 September 28 (Box 11)
  - David Arnold named representative of New Delhi Field Office, 1992 December 4 (Box 11)
  - Latinos: Speaking in their Own Voices, 1992 December 15 (Box 11)
  - Linda B. Strumpf named Vice President, succeeds john W. English as head of investment division, 1992 December 18 (Box 11)
- News Releases, 1993-1995 (Box 11)
  - New World demands new approaches to U.N. funding, says international advisory group, 1993 February 23 (Box 11)
  - 76 Public programs names innovations award semifinalists by the Ford Foundation and Harvard University, 1993 (Box 11)
  - Ford Foundation grants $2.15 million to support Native American projects, 1993 June 1 (Box 11)
  - 25 State and local initiatives names finalists in seventh annual innovations awards program, 1993 (Box 11)
  - Ford Foundation – Kennedy School of Government, 1993 innovations awards program finalists (Box 11)
  - Innovations awards winners named, 1993 October 4 (Box 11)
  - United Negro Colleges Fund’s Campaign 2000 receives $5.4 million Ford Foundation grant, 1993 (Box 11)
  - Timothy Bork named Director of Africa and Middle East Programs, 1993 (Box 11)
  - Ford Foundation names Kathryn S. Fuller and Wilma Mankiller as trustees, 1993 (Box 11)
  - Ford Foundation invites five cities to join community development partnership program, 1993 (Box 11)
  - 25 Public projects to receive Ford Foundation grants as finalists in 1994 Innovations award program, 1994 July 19 (Box 11)
  - Ford Foundation awards 42.5 million to arts stabilization, 1994 (Box 11)
  - Ford Foundation wards $2.5 million to AIDS partnership, 1994 (Box 11)
  - Ford Foundation names Ratan Naval Tata to Board of Trustees, 1994 (Box 11)
  - Blueprint for United Nations reform published by Ford Foundation and Dag Hammarskjold Foundation, 1994 July 13 (Box 11)
  - Ford Foundation begins $8 million project to help two-year colleges revitalize rural communities, 1994 (Box 11)
  - Franklin A. Thomas –stepping down, 1994 (Box 11)
  - Three foundations join forces in $5 million initiative to help improve analysis of state budget and fiscal policies, 1995 (Box 11)
  - 1995 Innovations in American government award winners named, 1995 October 26 (Box 11)